<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="tl"><body><pb facs="#f010"/>
			<div ana="#cat-stones" decls="#cat-stones">
				<head><seg ana="#rs-m">Counterfeit coral</seg> <note n="c_003r_02">In this period, counterfeit does not necessarily connote a deceptive practice of imitation. See <ref target="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/essays/ann_045_fa_16">Lores-Chavez, “Imitating Raw Nature.”</ref></note></head>
				<p>
					<metamark>+</metamark>
				</p>
				<p>One needs to first make the branches of <seg ana="#rs-m">wood</seg> or take a bizarre <seg ana="#rs-m">thorn branch</seg>, then melt a <seg ana="#rs-ms">lb</seg> of the most beautiful <seg ana="#rs-m">clear pitch resin</seg> and put in one <seg ana="#rs-ms">ounce</seg> of <seg ana="#rs-m">subtly ground vermilion</seg> with <seg ana="#rs-pa">walnut</seg> oil, and if you add in a little <seg ana="#rs-pl">Venice</seg> <seg ana="#rs-fr">laque platte</seg>, the color will be more vivid, and stir everything in the <seg ana="#rs-m">resin</seg> melted over a <seg ana="#rs-m">charcoal</seg> fire and not of flame, for fear that it catches fire. Next dip in your branches while turning, &amp; if any filaments should remain on it, turn the branch over the heat of the <seg ana="#rs-m">charcoal</seg>.</p>
				<p rend="left-top" style="tall"><seg ana="#rs-m">Colophony</seg> is nothing other than recooked <seg ana="#rs-m">resin</seg>. To do it well, take a <seg ana="#rs-m">leaded</seg> pot &amp; melt the <seg ana="#rs-m">resin</seg>, &amp; boil it over the <seg ana="#rs-tl">brazier</seg> a good <seg ana="#rs-tmp">hour</seg>, &amp; until it appears not to be thick, but clear &amp; liquid like <seg ana="#rs-m">water</seg>, &amp; easily runs &amp; flows from the tip of a <seg ana="#rs-tl">stick</seg> with which you grind it, &amp; test it. Then pour it through a <seg ana="#rs-m">coarse canvas</seg> or a <seg ana="#rs-m">very light tammy cloth</seg>, such that when pouring it falls into the strongest <seg ana="#rs-m">vinegar</seg> that you can find, for the <seg ana="#rs-m">vinegar</seg> gives it strength &amp; prevents it from being so fragile. Reiterate this two or three times &amp; it will be beautiful &amp; well purified. For counterfeiting your <seg ana="#rs-m">coral</seg>, you can mix a <seg ana="#rs-ms">quarter part</seg> of <seg ana="#rs-m">mastic</seg> into your <seg ana="#rs-m">purified resin</seg> to render it more firm and more beautiful, &amp; if you were to take a single tear of <seg ana="#rs-m">mastic</seg>, it would be all the better, but it would be too long.</p>
				<p rend="left-top"><seg ana="#rs-m">Sulfur</seg> &amp; <seg ana="#rs-m">vermilion</seg> makes the same effect.</p>
				<p rend="top">The <seg ana="#rs-m">coral</seg> made of <seg ana="#rs-m">gules red enamel</seg> endures the <seg ana="#rs-tl">file</seg> and polishing.</p>
				<p rend="right-top">It is made like <seg ana="#rs-m">cement</seg> that is stronger mixed with <seg ana="#rs-tl">pestled</seg> <del>than of</del> glass rather than with <seg ana="#rs-m">brick</seg>. Thus, here one mixes well <seg ana="#rs-tl">pestled</seg> <seg ana="#rs-m">gules red enamel</seg>, which is red in body, with the <seg ana="#rs-m">vermilion</seg>. Thus with all colors of <seg ana="#rs-m">enamels</seg>.</p>
			</div>
			<div ana="#cat-varnish" decls="#cat-varnish">
				<head><seg ana="#rs-m">Varnish</seg> for panels</head>
				<p>Take a <seg ana="#rs-ms">lb</seg> of <seg ana="#rs-pl">Venice</seg> turpentine &amp; heat it in a <seg ana="#rs-tl">pot</seg> until it simmers, and put in half a <seg ana="#rs-ms">lb</seg> of the <seg ana="#rs-m">turpentine oil</seg> of the whitest you can find, and stir it together well on a <seg ana="#rs-m">charcoal</seg> fire and take it off immediately. And <del><seg ana="#rs-fr">elle</seg></del> it is done. But if it seems too thick to you, add in a little more <seg ana="#rs-m">oil</seg>. Similarly if it is too clear, you can thicken it by putting in a little <seg ana="#rs-m">turpentine</seg>. Thus you will give it whatever body you want. It could be made well without fire, but, when heated, it is more desiccative. It is appropriate for panel paintings and other painted things without corrupting the colors or yellowing. And it dries both <seg ana="#rs-env">in the shade</seg> and <seg ana="#rs-env">in the sun</seg>, and <seg ana="#rs-tmp">overnight</seg>, and <seg ana="#rs-tmp">during the winter</seg> as well as <seg ana="#rs-tmp">in the summer</seg>. It is commonly sold 15 <seg ana="#rs-cn">sous</seg> a <seg ana="#rs-ms">lb</seg>.</p>
				<p rend="left-bottom" style="tall">A little more <seg ana="#rs-m">turpentine</seg> than <seg ana="#rs-m">turpentine oil</seg> is needed in order to give body to the <seg ana="#rs-m">varnish</seg>, which needs to be applied with the <seg ana="#rs-bp">finger</seg> in order to spread it thinner and less thick, for when it is thick, it turns yellow and sticks. One does not <seg ana="#rs-m">varnish</seg> to make paintings shine, for it just takes the light out of them.</p>
			</div>
			<div ana="#cat-varnish" decls="#cat-varnish">
				<head><seg ana="#rs-m">Thick varnish</seg> for planks</head>
				<p>There is a <seg ana="#rs-m">varnish</seg> that takes a long time to dry &amp; drips more than two <seg ana="#rs-tmp">months</seg> after it has been applied to the planks. But this one does not drip like that of <seg ana="#rs-tmp">times past</seg>, which was made of <seg ana="#rs-m">linseed oil</seg>, <seg ana="#rs-m">garlic</seg> boiled in it to extinguish it &amp; rid it of grease, &amp; with <seg ana="#rs-m">wheat</seg>. And this one yellowed &amp; rendered greenish the blue color of paintings. This one is made like the other one except that one puts <seg ana="#rs-m">coarse common turpentine</seg></p>
			</div>
			<div ana="#cat-varnish" decls="#cat-varnish">
				<p rend="left-bottom" style="wide">But it is used to heighten colors which have soaked in and to keep them from dust. <seg ana="#rs-m">Mastic varnish</seg> does not resist <seg ana="#rs-env">rain</seg>, whereas that of <seg ana="#rs-m">oil</seg> and <seg ana="#rs-m">rosin</seg> does.</p>
			</div>
			</body></text>