<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="translation"><body><pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_220"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_220_L1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} <persName>María Catarina</persName></head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-fourth day of the month of May of one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, six years old, a descendant of the Ute tribe from which the citizen <persName>José Mondragón</persName>, resident of the town of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>, rescued her. Her godparents were <persName>Felipe Nerio Maes</persName> and <persName>María del Refugio Pacheco</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_220_L3" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María de la Luz</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-sixth day of the month of June of one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: I, priest <persName>Don José de la Cruz Vigil</persName>, as curate, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a four-year-old child, and I named her <persName>María de la Luz</persName>. She is a descendant of the Ute tribe, servant of <persName>Don Juan Bolem</persName>, who rescued her, resident of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>Juan Bautista Bolem</persName> and <persName>María Luisa Archuleta</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed><persName>Antonio José Martínez</persName> {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_220_L4 #FHL_007548733_IMG_220_L4CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Serafina</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-sixth day of the month of June of the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: I, priest <persName>Don Antonio José de la Cruz Vigil</persName>, as curate, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, five years old, and I named her <persName>María Serafina</persName>. She is a descendant of the Ute tribe, servant of <persName>Don Juan Bolem</persName>, who rescued her, resident of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>Buenaventura Lobato</persName> and <persName>María Dolores Córdoba</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligations and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
				<signed>José Vigil {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_220_R1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} José Santiago</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName>, on the <date>twenty-sixth of the month of June of one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: Having been catechized according to what is prescribed for the baptism of adults, and having obtained competent instruction, I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, according to the special rituals, solemnly exorcized, baptized, placed holy oils and sacred chrism on an adult, about thirteen years of age, a descendant of the Ute tribe. He is a servant of <persName>Don Juan Roles</persName>, who rescued him a few years ago. He has been educated in his house in the neighborhood of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. I found him to be sufficiently instructed in the principles, means, and end of the Christian religion (and very enthusiastic, desirous, and aspiring to be received in her, with the faith and hope of obtaining eternal life). I named him <persName>José Santiago</persName>. His godparents were <persName>Manuel Antonio Sandoval</persName> and <persName>Margarita Martínez</persName>, all residents of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			</body></text>