<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="translation">
		<body>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_073"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_073_L1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} José Rafael</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>fifth day of the month of August of the year 1839</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a six-day-old child. I named him <persName>José Rafael</persName>, natural son of <persName>Guadalupe Vigil</persName>, an Indian servant of the late <persName>José Vigil</persName>, resident of the town of <placeName>La Santísima Trinidad de Arroyo Seco</placeName>. His godparents were <persName>Francisco Tomás [Bentos?]</persName> and <persName>María Soledad Vigil</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_076"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_076_L3" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} Juan Manuel</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>seventh day of the month of September of one thousand eight hundred and thirty-nine</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and chrism on an Indian child, seven or eight years old, who was rescued from the Ute tribe. Although it has been one year since he was rescued, he is still not sufficiently instructed, but being ill, and with the little that he has learned, he has effectively explained that he desires to join the religion of Jesus Christ. I verified that he is a servant of <persName>Don Charles Beaubien</persName>, resident of <placeName>San Fernández</placeName>. His godparents were <persName>Eugenio [Letendosen?]</persName> and <persName>María Rufina Vigil</persName>, also from San Fernández. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship. I signed it for the record. [^The name of the baptized child was <persName>Juan Manuel</persName>]</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_103"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_103_R3" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Soledad</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-third day of the month of March of the year one thousand eight hundred and forty</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, in urgent need due to illness, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on an adult woman, about twenty years of age, which I did according to the rite of our Holy Mother Church regarding the baptism of adults. Having previously started catechism, she was found moderately instructed in the principles, means, and ends of our holy religion, enough for her to be granted her request to become a Christian, in the condition that she was in. I named her <persName>María Soledad</persName>. She is a descendant of the Navajo tribe and a servant of Señora <persName>María Teodora Romero</persName>, who rescued her. The same Señora María Teodora Romero was her godmother, along with her son, <persName>Jorge Antonio</persName>, of the town of <placeName>San Fernando</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship. I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_120"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_120_L1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Gabriela</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>thirteenth day of the month of August of one thousand eight hundred and forty</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized a child, two years old, whom I named <persName>María Gabriela</persName>, rescued from the Paiute nation and servant of <persName>José Gabriel Gallegos</persName>. Her godparents were <persName>José Nazario Gallegos</persName> and <persName>María Antonia Gallegos</persName>, residents of <placeName>Arroyo Seco</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship. I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_185"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_185_R2" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} José Miguel</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>third day of the month of November of one thousand eight hundred and forty-one</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, five years old. I gave him the name <persName>José Miguel</persName>, an Indian rescued from the Ute tribe. He is a servant of <persName>Juan Antonio Abeyta</persName>, and his godfather was <persName>Pablo Garduño</persName>, both residents of the town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe</placeName>. I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_194"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_194_L1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} <persName>José de la Cruz</persName></head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>second day of the month of February of the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, received a request from the previous year to become a Christian from an adult male, 30 years old, descendant of the Jicarilla tribe. I had advised him that he should be instructed in the knowledge of the principal mysteries of our holy faith and religion, and in the commandments or precepts that Christians accept as their obligation, and the motives for wanting to become a Christian, warning him that the main purpose was to serve God in this life and afterward, to see Him, and to enjoy in the blessedness that He has for his chosen ones in the hereafter. As of this date, he had completed the corresponding catechisms. I found him to be instructed in the principles, means, and ends of our holy religion, and that he was determined to become a Christian so that God would forgive all of his sins incurred up to the present time. [I found him] to be able to receive the other sacraments, ready to serve him faithfully from here on out in order to achieve eternal glory until the end of his days; that he will no longer believe in things of gentilism, of its errors and idolatries, but only in the true God. Now, by means of baptism, he tries to acknowledge and adore him with greater efficiency. By virtue of the authority that I have been granted by my ecclesiastic superior, I exorcized, placed holy oils, baptized him, and anointed him with chrism, all solemnly, according to the rite for the baptism of adults of our Holy Mother Church. His godparents were <persName>Francisco Esteban Vigil</persName> and <persName>María Rosalía Gallegos</persName>, residents of the town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de los Dolores</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_220"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_220_L1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} <persName>María Catarina</persName></head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-fourth day of the month of May of one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, six years old, a descendant of the Ute tribe from which the citizen <persName>José Mondragón</persName>, resident of the town of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>, rescued her. Her godparents were <persName>Felipe Nerio Maes</persName> and <persName>María del Refugio Pacheco</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_220_L3" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María de la Luz</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-sixth day of the month of June of one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: I, priest <persName>Don José de la Cruz Vigil</persName>, as curate, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a four-year-old child, and I named her <persName>María de la Luz</persName>. She is a descendant of the Ute tribe, servant of <persName>Don Juan Bolem</persName>, who rescued her, resident of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>Juan Bautista Bolem</persName> and <persName>María Luisa Archuleta</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed><persName>Antonio José Martínez</persName> {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_220_L4 #FHL_007548733_IMG_220_L4CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Serafina</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-sixth day of the month of June of the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: I, priest <persName>Don Antonio José de la Cruz Vigil</persName>, as curate, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, five years old, and I named her <persName>María Serafina</persName>. She is a descendant of the Ute tribe, servant of <persName>Don Juan Bolem</persName>, who rescued her, resident of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>Buenaventura Lobato</persName> and <persName>María Dolores Córdoba</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligations and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
				<signed>José Vigil {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_220_R1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} José Santiago</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName>, on the <date>twenty-sixth of the month of June of one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: Having been catechized according to what is prescribed for the baptism of adults, and having obtained competent instruction, I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, according to the special rituals, solemnly exorcized, baptized, placed holy oils and sacred chrism on an adult, about thirteen years of age, a descendant of the Ute tribe. He is a servant of <persName>Don Juan Roles</persName>, who rescued him a few years ago. He has been educated in his house in the neighborhood of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. I found him to be sufficiently instructed in the principles, means, and end of the Christian religion (and very enthusiastic, desirous, and aspiring to be received in her, with the faith and hope of obtaining eternal life). I named him <persName>José Santiago</persName>. His godparents were <persName>Manuel Antonio Sandoval</persName> and <persName>Margarita Martínez</persName>, all residents of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_232"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_232_R2" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Florentina</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>sixteenth day of the month of October of one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a one-day-old infant. I named her <persName>María Florentina</persName>, natural daughter of an Indian servant of Señora <persName>Ignacia Jaramillo</persName>, resident of the town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>Francisco Jaramillo</persName> and <persName>María Romualda de Luna</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_243"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_243_L2" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} Catarina</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName>, on the <date>eleventh day of the month of January of one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, out of extreme necessity, having certified her by virtue of catechisms and assessed her intention and desire of becoming a Christian, solemnly exorcised, baptized, and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on an adult, sixteen years old. I named her <persName>Catarina</persName>. She is an Indian servant of <persName>Don Juan Manuel Lucero</persName>, resident of the town of <placeName>San Francisco de Paula</placeName>. He himself was the godparent, along with his wife <persName>Juana María Martínez</persName>. I advised them of their obligation that, as masters of said servant, and also as godparents, they had to give and take care of her education, to teach her Christian duties, and the spiritual kinship that they contracted. I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_281"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_281_L4" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} José Manuel</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twelfth day of the month of November of one thousand eight hundred and forty-three</date>: I, parish priest <placeName>Don Antonio José Martínez</placeName>, according to the rite of our Holy Mother Church for baptizing adults, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on an Indian child, ten years old, who was rescued from the tribe of the north. I named him <persName>José Manuel</persName>. He is a servant of <persName>Don Gabriel Abeyta</persName>, who himself was the godparent, along with his wife, <persName>María de la Encarnación Romero</persName>, residents of the town of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_284"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_284_R1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} Juan Francisco</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>tenth day of the month of December of one thousand eight hundred and forty-three</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, one month old. I named him <persName>Juan Francisco</persName>, descendant of the Ute tribe from which he was rescued. He is a servant of <persName>Antonio Díaz Armenta</persName> and <persName>María Isabel Sánchez</persName>. His godparents were <persName>Juan Antonio Madrid</persName> and <persName>María Manuela Romero</persName>, all residents of the town of <placeName>Río Colorado</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_308"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_308_R3 #FHL_007548733_IMG_309_CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Antonia</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>fourteenth day of the month of April of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on an adult, thirteen years old, of the Navajo tribe. I named her <persName>María Antonia</persName>, servant of <persName>Miguel Mascareñas</persName>, both residents of the town of <placeName>Santa Gertrudis</placeName>.</p>
				<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_309"/>
				<p>This baptism was according to the rite of our Holy Mother Church with the catechism and approval already having taken place. The godparents were <persName>Nazario Aguilar</persName> and <persName>María de la Cruz Mascareñas</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed> Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_333"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_333_L3" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Josefa</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-fifth day of the month of August of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, seven years old. She is of the Ute tribe, from whom she was rescued. She is a servant of <persName>Don Juan Manuel Lucero</persName> and <persName>Doña Juana María Martínez</persName>, the same were her godparents. They are residents of the town of <placeName>San Francisco de Paula</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record. Her name is <persName>María Josefa</persName>.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_333_R1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Dolores</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-fifth day of the month of August of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, according to the rite for the baptism of adults of our Holy Mother Church, solemnly baptized, exorcised, placed holy oils and sacred chrism on an adult, twelve years old. I named her <persName>María Dolores</persName>. She is an Indian of the Navajo tribe from which she was rescued. The steps of catechism were carried out and she was found well instructed in the principles, means, and ends of our holy religion. Desiring to be admitted to this practice through the holy sacrament of baptism, she recanted the errors and principles that she had acquired in her gentile sect, being completely willing and with the strongest resolution to live in observance of this Christian religion, which is conferred upon her in baptism. She is a servant of <persName>José del Espiritu Santo Córdoba</persName>. Her godparents were <persName>José Dolores Durán</persName> and <persName>Juana María de Gracia Sánchez</persName>, all residents of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_353"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_353_L1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} José Matías</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>third day of the month of October of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: Having carried out the corresponding catechisms until found to be well-instructed in the principles, means, and ends of our holy religion, I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly exorcised, baptized, placed holy oils and sacred chrism on an adult, eight years old, according to the rite of our Holy Mother Church for the baptism of adults. I named him <persName>José Matías</persName>. He is a servant of <persName>Fernando Trujillo</persName> and <persName>Juana María Trujillo</persName>, residents of the town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe</placeName>. The same were also his godparents. The said adult is a descendant of the Ute tribe from which he was rescued. I advised the said godparents and masters of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_353_L2 #FHL_007548733_IMG_353_L2CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Antonia</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>third day of the month of October of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, four years old. I named her <persName>María Antonia</persName>. She is Indian, descendant of the Ute tribe from which she was rescued. She is a servant of <persName>Doña María Rafaela Varela</persName>, resident of the town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>Pablo Valdez</persName> and <persName>María Magdalena Gallegos</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_354"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_354_L2 #FHL_007548733_IMG_354_L2CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} Juan Lorenzo</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>fourth day of the month of October of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a six-year-old child of the Ute tribe from which he was rescued. I named him <persName>Juan Lorenzo</persName>. He is a servant of <persName>Juan Ignacio Martínez</persName>, both residents of the town of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>Benito Martínez</persName> and <persName>María Rosalía Mascareñas</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_354_R1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Soledad</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>fourth day of the month of October of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, five years old. I named her <persName>María Soledad</persName>. She is a descendant of the Ute tribe, servant of <persName>Juan Ignacio Martínez</persName>, resident of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>José Rafael Martínez</persName> and <persName>María Rosa Martínez</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_354_R2 #FHL_007548733_IMG_355_CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} Juan Francisco</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>fifth day of the month of October of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a foundling child who yesterday morning appeared in the town of <placeName>Sangre de Cristo</placeName> next to the house of <persName>Felipe Nerio Maes</persName> who picked him up and sheltered him. There was no sign that he had been baptized. [He was] wrapped and completely bundled in a piece of an old sarape. As he was unable to learn who the mother was, he and his wife, <persName>María del Refugio Pacheco</persName>, took the child from said</p>
				<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_355"/>
				<p>place as their own. I named him <persName>José Francisco</persName>. The godparents were <persName>Antonio Cruz Vigil</persName> and <persName>Juana María Vigil</persName>, residents of the town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_376"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_376_R1 #FHL_007548733_IMG_377_CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Luisa</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>second day of the month of January of the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName> solemnly baptized, placed holy oils and sacred chrism on an adult, about thirty years old, according to the rite of our Holy Mother Church for the baptism of adults. I named her <persName>María Luisa</persName>. She is an Indian rescued from the Ute tribe whose baptism was preceded by the corresponding catechisms until she was well instructed in the principles, means, and ends of our holy Christian religion. She embraced it affectionately and fervently, and she abjured and renounced any errors of the barbarian gentiles in which she had been instructed. The said Indian is a servant of <persName>Don Charles Beaubien</persName> and Señora <persName>María Paula Lobato</persName>, residents of <placeName>San Fernando</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>Feliz [Nontin]</persName> and <persName>Luz Trujillo</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of</p>
				<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_377"/>
				<p>their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_407"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_407_L2 #FHL_007548733_IMG_407_L2CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Soledad</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-fourth day of the month of March of one thousand eight hundred and forty-five</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a two-day-old child. I named her <persName>María Soledad</persName>. She is the natural daughter of <persName>María Guadalupe Bent</persName>, an Indian servant of <persName>Charles Bent</persName>, who had been rescued from the nations of the north. The godparents were <persName>Elfego Bent</persName> and <persName>María Romualda Luna</persName>, residents of the town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_470"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_470_R2 #FHL_007548733_IMG_471_R2CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Soledad</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>San Jerónimo de Taos</placeName> on the <date>fifth day of the month of November of the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-five</date>: Having already carried out the necessary catechisms for the instruction of an adult, and having found her sufficiently instructed in the principles, means, and ends of our religion, as well as determined to be baptized for her own honest motives that should [ILL], I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly exorcised, placed holy oils, baptized, and anointed with sacred chrism an adult, about twenty years old, according to the rite that Our Holy Mother Church prescribes for the baptism of adults. She is a descendant of the Ute tribe from which she was rescued, servant of <persName>Don Charles Beaubien</persName> and <persName>Doña María Paula Lobato</persName>, residents of the town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>José Antonio López</persName> and <persName>María de Luz Beaubien</persName>. I named her <persName>María Soledad</persName>, and I</p>
				<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_471"/>
				<p>advised the godparents of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_500"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_500_L1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Margarita</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>first day of the month of March of one thousand eight hundred and forty-six</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName> solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, two years old. I named her <persName>María Margarita</persName>. A descendant of the Navajo tribe from which she was rescued. She is a servant of <persName>José Dolores Córdoba</persName> and <persName>María Ramona Martínez</persName>, residents of the town of <placeName>Sangre de Cristo</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>José Felipe Nerio Maes</persName> and <persName>María del Refugio Pacheco</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_515"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_515_R2 #FHL_007548733_IMG_516_CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Rosalía</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twelfth day of the month of April of the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-six</date>: Having already carried out the corresponding catechisms until I certified her to be instructed in the principles, means, and ends of our holy religion, and having the pious affection of becoming a Christian and observing the precepts, I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly exorcised, placed holy oils, baptized and anointed with sacred chrism an adult, according to the rites of our Holy Church for the baptism of adults. I named her <persName>María Rosalía</persName>. She is a servant of <persName>Don Juan de Jesús Mares</persName>, resident of the town of <placeName>San Francisco de Paula</placeName>.</p>
				<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_516"/>
				<p>The said adult is a descendant of the Ute tribe, from which she was rescued. The godparents were <persName>Juan de los Reyes Mares</persName> and <persName>María de la Luz Trujillo</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship. She herself understands that she is to observe and keep the doctrine of our holy religion. I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_540"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_540_L1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Rosalía</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twentieth day of the month of June of one thousand eight hundred and forty-six</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, five years old. I named her <persName>María Rosalía</persName>, descendant of the Navajo tribe from which she was rescued. She is a servant of <persName>Francisco Salazar</persName> and <persName>María Manuela Vigil</persName>, residents of the town of <placeName>La Santísima Trinidad</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>Luciano Salazar</persName> and <persName>María de la Concepción Salazar</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_541"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_541_L1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} Juana María</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-first day of the month of June of one thousand eight-hundred and forty-six</date>: Having already carried out the corresponding catechisms until I certified her to be instructed in the principles, means, and ends of our holy religion, and having the pious affection of becoming a Christian and observing the precepts, I, priest <persName>Don Eulogio Valdez</persName>, with permission from the parish priest, solemnly exorcised, placed holy oils, baptized and anointed [her] with sacred chrism according to the rites of our Holy Church for the baptism of adults. I named her <persName>Juana María</persName>, a servant of <persName>Doña María Rafaela Varela</persName>, resident of this town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe</placeName>. The said adult is a descendant of the Ute tribe from which she was rescued. The godparents were <persName>Don Juan de Jesús Valdez</persName> and <persName>María Juliana Trujillo</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligations and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Eulogio Valdez {rubric}</signed>
				<signed><persName>Antonio José Martínez</persName> {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>