<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="translation"><body><pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_353"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_353_L1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} José Matías</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>third day of the month of October of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: Having carried out the corresponding catechisms until found to be well-instructed in the principles, means, and ends of our holy religion, I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly exorcised, baptized, placed holy oils and sacred chrism on an adult, eight years old, according to the rite of our Holy Mother Church for the baptism of adults. I named him <persName>José Matías</persName>. He is a servant of <persName>Fernando Trujillo</persName> and <persName>Juana María Trujillo</persName>, residents of the town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe</placeName>. The same were also his godparents. The said adult is a descendant of the Ute tribe from which he was rescued. I advised the said godparents and masters of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_353_L2 #FHL_007548733_IMG_353_L2CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Antonia</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>third day of the month of October of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, four years old. I named her <persName>María Antonia</persName>. She is Indian, descendant of the Ute tribe from which she was rescued. She is a servant of <persName>Doña María Rafaela Varela</persName>, resident of the town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>Pablo Valdez</persName> and <persName>María Magdalena Gallegos</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			</body></text>