<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="translation"><body><pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_354"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_354_L2 #FHL_007548733_IMG_354_L2CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} Juan Lorenzo</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>fourth day of the month of October of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a six-year-old child of the Ute tribe from which he was rescued. I named him <persName>Juan Lorenzo</persName>. He is a servant of <persName>Juan Ignacio Martínez</persName>, both residents of the town of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>Benito Martínez</persName> and <persName>María Rosalía Mascareñas</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_354_R1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Soledad</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>fourth day of the month of October of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, five years old. I named her <persName>María Soledad</persName>. She is a descendant of the Ute tribe, servant of <persName>Juan Ignacio Martínez</persName>, resident of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. The godparents were <persName>José Rafael Martínez</persName> and <persName>María Rosa Martínez</persName>, residents of the same place. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_354_R2 #FHL_007548733_IMG_355_CONT" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} Juan Francisco</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>fifth day of the month of October of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a foundling child who yesterday morning appeared in the town of <placeName>Sangre de Cristo</placeName> next to the house of <persName>Felipe Nerio Maes</persName> who picked him up and sheltered him. There was no sign that he had been baptized. [He was] wrapped and completely bundled in a piece of an old sarape. As he was unable to learn who the mother was, he and his wife, <persName>María del Refugio Pacheco</persName>, took the child from said</p>
				</div></body></text>