<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><pb facs="#f012"/>
<ab>
<lb/>
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>or linen &amp; leave it thus for xx4
<lb/>hours &amp; it will be engraved. But if you should
<lb/>want to engrave promptly, varnish all your work &amp; boil it in the
<lb/>said liquor, &amp; it will promptly engrave.
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>Steel mirrors
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>X They are called of steel because in times
<lb/>past they were commonly made of steel polished with
<lb/>emery putty. But more easily, various kinds are made
<lb/>with cuivre franc, which is rosette &amp;
<lb/>tin, because it is cast in a mold &amp; made
<lb/>round, concave, convex &amp; however one likes, to represent various
<lb/>forms.
<lb/>    
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>So take half rosette copper &amp; half
<lb/>soft tin, that is to say fine, which has not yet been used.
<lb/>Put them in a crucible, &amp; first melt the copper
<lb/>well. And once it is well melted, put in the tin and mix
<lb/>together. Then cast in the mold, of white stone with no
<lb/>eyelets, &amp; anoint the mold with oil, &amp; let
<lb/>it be moderately warm. Then, having
<lb/>molded your mirror, you can polish it in this way.
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>Set one of these in plaster in order that it holds firmly,
<lb/>&amp; then put the other one over it with thin sand in between,
<lb/>&amp; rub one against the other, whether it be concave or flat, &amp; thus you
<lb/>will polish two at once. And if you want to polish them on both sides,
<lb/>you only need to switch them, that is to say put the one that was
<lb/>polishing into the plaster &amp; the one that was in the
<lb/>plaster to polish. After having polished them with the
<lb/>arene you can smooth them with Venice tripoli, 
<lb/>which should not be sandy, &amp; next with
<lb/>putty. You polish with
<lb/>arene using water, but polishing with
<lb/>tripoli &amp; putty is done
<lb/>dry. Once polished, you can set it.
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>Concave mirrors
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>The concave mirror composed in the aforesaid form produces an
<lb/>endless number of pretty conceits which seem magic. If someone wants to see
<lb/>oneself from behind, it is necessary to place the concave
<lb/>mirror on the ground on its foot, &amp; let it be at a slant;
<lb/>next, look at it from one pace away. But if you
<lb/>look at it close up, it will represent you the right way up but
<lb/>with your face quite large &amp; the hairs of your
<lb/>beard as thick as
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>
</ab>

</body></text>