<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="transcription"><body><pb facs="#f013"/>
<div facs="#f013"><ab>
<lb/>
</ab></div>
<div facs="#f013"><ab>
<lb/>string &amp; will represent a nipple as large as a plate, and
<lb/>women can see the secret places that they do not
<lb/>want to show to surgeons. It casts the representation out of
<lb/>itself, and if you touch &lt;-the place-&gt; the eye of
<lb/>the representation with your finger, another finger
<lb/>will come against yours.
</ab></div>
<div facs="#f013"><ab>
<lb/>You will make a light at night for someone quite far
<lb/>away, if you place the concave mirror behind a candle
<lb/>placed on the window. You will be able to read and write quite
<lb/>far from the candle if you place it behind the candle
<lb/>&amp; place &amp; turn the concavity toward you. If you put
<lb/>the mirror at the end of a table &amp; a
<lb/>candle on it, it will represent two lights on the
<lb/>table for you. To see what is happening on a street,
<lb/>shutter the window, whereby the more of it you can shut the
<lb/>better it will be. Make a hole at the lower one, as wide as your little
<lb/>finger, perfectly round, from one side to the other. Then
<lb/>place a sheet of paper on the window
<lb/>&amp; let the middle of the sheet be over the hole.
<lb/>Pierce the sheet in the same place as the hole &amp; the same
<lb/>size. After, place the concave face of the mirror toward the
<lb/>hole, &amp; it will represent to you all those who pass by in the
<lb/>street on the sheet of paper. Similarly with
<lb/>the pierced door of a closed room. You can make wavy ones
<lb/>&amp; triangular ones, in the fashion that Ptolemy describes, &amp;
<lb/>Archimedes. The concave one also sets fire to straw from
<lb/>quite far away, and lights a candle with the sun. Also, 
<lb/>it heats through the reverberation of fire.
</ab></div>
<div facs="#f013"><ab>
<lb/>For bronzing in yellow and white
</ab></div>
<div facs="#f013"><ab>
<lb/>Take looking-glass tin and melt it. On half a lb of
<lb/>this, put half an ounce of quicksilver, and remove it
<lb/>all at once from the fire &amp; grind it, and it will be like
<lb/>ash. &lt;-Grind-&gt; Wash it quite well in clean water.
<lb/>Next, grind it on marble &amp; temper it with water of
<lb/>&lt;-ret-&gt; hide glue. Next, apply to
<lb/>your wooden candlesticks &amp; any other work you like,
<lb/>&amp; burnish with the tooth. You can grind pin filings
<lb/>&amp; apply them with the said glue. 
</ab></div>
<div facs="#f013"><ab>
<lb/>
</ab></div>

  </body>
      </text>