<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="text"><body><div><pb facs="#f011"/>
<ab>
<lb/>
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>Black varnish for sword guard, bands for trunks,
<lb/>&amp;c
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>Take linseed oil or more cheaply, walnut
<lb/>oil, and rid it of grease with garlic &amp;
<lb/>&lt;-onions-&gt; +hog’s
<lb/>fennel, some also add bread crusts, which you will
<lb/>boil in it for a good quarter of an hour. Next, put
<lb/>in one lb of the oil thus boiled the size of a walnut of black
<lb/>pitch &amp; a double handful of grains of wheat, without
<lb/>removing the garlic &amp; onions, and let
<lb/>it boil together for a good quarter of an hour. And
<lb/>when the pitch is well melted &amp; when the oil has body,
<lb/>you can remove it from the fire. Then, to varnish, place your
<lb/>iron over a low charcoal fire &amp; apply your
<lb/>varnish with a feather or a brush.
<lb/>And when you see that it no longer smokes, it is done and your
<lb/>varnish is dry.
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>For excellent black varnish, add two or three paternoster
<lb/>beads of jet among the rest.
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>Some consider walnut oil better.
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>If there is a lot of varnish, it needs to boil for at least
<lb/>half a day, for it is better the more it boils. It
<lb/>is dangerous if it catches fire, if it goes over the top, and is
<lb/>hard to extinguish. Make this therefore in a courtyard or an
<lb/>open space.
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/> 
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>In five or six lb of oil, one must put one lb
<lb/>of galipot, which costs 4 sous, &amp; some
<lb/>peeled garlic cloves. This varnish in and of
<lb/>itself is not black, but it blackens over the fire.
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>See below, around the 3rd part of this book,
<lb/>after sands, in the chapter on furbishers.
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>Black varnish without fire, without disassembling the
<lb/>harnesses or removing the bands from
<lb/>trunks
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>Take varnish of spike lavender oil &amp; mix in
<lb/>soot black or lampblack, &amp; without fire it will mix in
<lb/>by itself. Varnish with a brush &amp; it will soon be
<lb/>dry. Turpentine varnish will be quite good, but it does not dry
<lb/>as soon.
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>Varnish of iron engravers
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>Take linseed oil or walnut oil
<lb/>&amp;, in place of black pitch, you will put in a little
<lb/>pitch resin, &amp; it needs to be cooked in the fashion of black
<lb/>varnish on fire. And for applying it, heat your iron &amp;
<lb/>give it only one layer of varnish, &amp; when it no longer
<lb/>smokes, it is dry. Next engrave with a steel point
<lb/>whatever you want. Next take salt &amp;
<lb/>verdigris &amp; mix as much of one as of the other in quite
<lb/>strong vinegar &amp; leave it for xx4 hours
<lb/>before using it, &amp; all will be tempered. Next spread some of this
<lb/>liquor or sauce on the engraved object with a sponge
</ab>
<ab>
<lb/>
</ab>

  </div></body>
      </text>