<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="translation"><body><pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_333"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_333_L3" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Josefa</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-fifth day of the month of August of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, solemnly baptized and placed holy oils and sacred chrism on a child, seven years old. She is of the Ute tribe, from whom she was rescued. She is a servant of <persName>Don Juan Manuel Lucero</persName> and <persName>Doña Juana María Martínez</persName>, the same were her godparents. They are residents of the town of <placeName>San Francisco de Paula</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record. Her name is <persName>María Josefa</persName>.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_333_R1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} María Dolores</head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>twenty-fifth day of the month of August of one thousand eight hundred and forty-four</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, according to the rite for the baptism of adults of our Holy Mother Church, solemnly baptized, exorcised, placed holy oils and sacred chrism on an adult, twelve years old. I named her <persName>María Dolores</persName>. She is an Indian of the Navajo tribe from which she was rescued. The steps of catechism were carried out and she was found well instructed in the principles, means, and ends of our holy religion. Desiring to be admitted to this practice through the holy sacrament of baptism, she recanted the errors and principles that she had acquired in her gentile sect, being completely willing and with the strongest resolution to live in observance of this Christian religion, which is conferred upon her in baptism. She is a servant of <persName>José del Espiritu Santo Córdoba</persName>. Her godparents were <persName>José Dolores Durán</persName> and <persName>Juana María de Gracia Sánchez</persName>, all residents of <placeName>San Francisco del Rancho</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			</body></text>