<text xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="translation"><body><pb facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_194"/>
			<div facs="#FHL_007548733_IMG_194_L1" type="Baptism">
				<head>{left margin} <persName>José de la Cruz</persName></head>
				<p>In this parish of <placeName>Taos</placeName> on the <date>second day of the month of February of the year one thousand eight hundred and forty-two</date>: I, parish priest <persName>Don Antonio José Martínez</persName>, received a request from the previous year to become a Christian from an adult male, 30 years old, descendant of the Jicarilla tribe. I had advised him that he should be instructed in the knowledge of the principal mysteries of our holy faith and religion, and in the commandments or precepts that Christians accept as their obligation, and the motives for wanting to become a Christian, warning him that the main purpose was to serve God in this life and afterward, to see Him, and to enjoy in the blessedness that He has for his chosen ones in the hereafter. As of this date, he had completed the corresponding catechisms. I found him to be instructed in the principles, means, and ends of our holy religion, and that he was determined to become a Christian so that God would forgive all of his sins incurred up to the present time. [I found him] to be able to receive the other sacraments, ready to serve him faithfully from here on out in order to achieve eternal glory until the end of his days; that he will no longer believe in things of gentilism, of its errors and idolatries, but only in the true God. Now, by means of baptism, he tries to acknowledge and adore him with greater efficiency. By virtue of the authority that I have been granted by my ecclesiastic superior, I exorcized, placed holy oils, baptized him, and anointed him with chrism, all solemnly, according to the rite for the baptism of adults of our Holy Mother Church. His godparents were <persName>Francisco Esteban Vigil</persName> and <persName>María Rosalía Gallegos</persName>, residents of the town of <placeName>Nuestra Señora de los Dolores</placeName>. I advised them of their obligation and spiritual kinship, and I signed it for the record.</p>
				<signed>Antonio José Martínez {rubric}</signed>
			</div>
			</body></text>